Guide to the Records of the Manhattanville Program RG 20
New York University Archives
Guide to the Records of the Manhattanville Program
Bulk, 1977-1979
1954-1983
RG 20
New York University Archives
2.0 linear feet
In September 1977, NYU and Manhattanville College (located in Purchase, NY) began offering joint master's programs in NYU's Graduate School of Arts and Science (GSAS) and Graduate School of Business Administration (GSBA). The programs were designed for part-time students with family and/or work responsibilities and to enable currently employed professionals to further their education and increase their knowledge in their specific field.
Arrangement
This collection has not been processed, and the files are ordered as they were received.
General Files
Physical Access
Please note that this collection is stored offsite, and you must contact the repository to schedule access.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of two boxes containing advertisements, correspondence, and reports about NYU's cooperation with Manhattanville College in establishing graduate programs in the arts and sciences and business.
History of the Manhattanville Progam
In September 1977, NYU and Manhattanville College (Purchase, NY) began offering joint master's programs in NYU's Graduate School of Arts and Science (GSAS) and Graduate School of Business Administration (GSBA). The programs were designed for part-time students with family and/or work responsibilities and to enable currently employed professionals to further their education and increase their knowledge in their specific field. Programs lasted two to three years, and NYU conferred the degrees and controlled the curriculum. Classes were initially taught by NYU faculty, but gradually, select Manhattanville professors taught introductory courses. Courses were offered at both NYU and Manhattanville campuses.
Manhattanville sought to overcome inflation issues and decreasing enrollment through inter-institutional cooperation with NYU. On April 29, 1977, the New York Board of Regents voted to amend NYU's charter and master plan authorizing establishment of a program in general management at Manhattanville leading to a Masters in Business Administration (MBA). In June 1977 the Board approved the remaining joint master's programs programs. GSAS offered a Master of Arts in Music and Psychology and an Master of Science in Biology, Chemistry (Organic or Physical), Computer Science, and Mathematics. GSBA offered an MBA program. In 1978, a graduate program in journalism began. NYU's School of Education, Health, Nursing, and Arts Professions (SEHNAP) also offered graduate credit courses from The Center for Safety, as well as courses on early childhood and elementary education, educational administration and supervision, home economics and nutrition, and leisure studies. The School of Continuing Education (SCE) offered 12 non-credit courses from the division of Career and Professional Development in publicity, personnel, communications, finance, data processing and systems analysis, and real estate.
The first student to complete a joint NYU/Manhattanville program graduated in June 1979. The programs signified the first time NYU's GSAS and GSBA offered degrees at another college and the first time Manhattanville awarded degrees other than its own.
Access Restrictions
Institutional records of New York University are closed for a period of 20 years from the date of their creation (the date on which each document was written). Board of Trustees records are similarly closed for 35 years from the date of creation. The opening date for files spanning several years will be 20 years from the most recent date. Access will be given to material already 20 years old contained within a collection that is not yet open when such material can be isolated from the rest of the collection.
Materials related to personnel, faculty grievances, job searches and all files with information that falls under the University's Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) policy are permanently restricted.
This collection is in
off-site storage
.
Manhattanville College.; New York (State). Board of Regents.; New York University.; Advertisements.; Correspondence.; New York (State) |x Purchase.; New York (State) |z New York.; New York University. Graduate School of Arts and Science.; New York University. Graduate School of Business Administration.; New York University. Graduate School of Public Administration.; New York University. School of Continuing Education.; New York University. School of Education, Health, Nursing, and Arts Profession.; Reports.
- Series I: General Files
  - Lisa Rich, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General note
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04226123 3
  - Elizabeth J. LoSacco/Manhattanville, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Lucadamo, Beth - Program Assistant, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Morris, Deborah L., undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Kleinbaum, Louise - Manhattanville Coordinator, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Computer Science - Juan Vega, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Vega-Calderon, Juan, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Tucket, Leo - Manhattanville, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Advertising/Manhattanville, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Ad Campaign, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Bulletin Copy, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Bulletin Copy, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Biology Brochure, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Biology Termination, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Biology Faculty, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Weekly Stats, Manhattanville, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Weekly Stats, Manhattanville, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Weekly Stats, Manhattanville, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Summer Session, Manhattanville, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Rent, Spring, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Spring, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Fall, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Summer, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Spring, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Time Files, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Time File, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Coordinator/Recruitment, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Administrative Secretary, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Fall, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Summer, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Spring, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Advertising Campaign, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Annual Report, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Faculty Appointment Forms, undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Chemistry - NYU/Manhattanville, undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Chemistry Faculty, undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Summer Session, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Summer Session, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Point Count, Spring, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Point Count, Fall, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Point Count, Summer, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Point Count, Spring, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Point Count, Fall, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Summer Session, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Point Count, Spring, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Computer Room Usage Table, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Manhattanville, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Manhattanville, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Manhattanville, undated (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Manhattanville, Fall, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Manhattanville, Summer, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - 6 Month Report, undated (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Other Programs in Westchester, undated (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Summer, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Appointments, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Salaries and Fringe Benefits, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Honorarium, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Lab and Instructional Supplies, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Service Publication Brochures, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Advertising, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Books and Periodicals, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Equipment (Empty), 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Travel and Living, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Dinner and Meetings, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Computer Services, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Untitled, undated (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Summer, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Spring, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Fall, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Summer Session, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Anderson, Nancy, undated (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Catalogs, undated (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Flyers, undated (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - High School Math Mailing List, undated (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Inquiry Mailing List, undated (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Mailing List, undated (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Psychology Personnel List, undated (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Manhattanville, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04226124 1
  - Manhattanville, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Applications and Procedures, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Bio Letter/William Beers, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Budget, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Calendar, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Chemistry Termination, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Coordinator, Grad Program, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Coordinator Search, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Fall, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Courses, Fall, Spring, Summer, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Master Mailing Lists, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - General Information, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - MBA, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Bio, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Computer Science, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Chemistry, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Music, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Psychology, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Manhattanville Projects - Chemistry, Journalism, Math, Music, Psychology, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Biology, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Computer Science, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Manhattanville Project, undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Promotion and Media Schedule, undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Manhattanville Strategy, undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Registration, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 26)